oh hello welcome to fix the world Friday
which also can be on the agenda rather
we're calling it that from now on I'm
joined today by Bentley who joined me
last week and G and I can let them
introduce themselves I feel like nobody
knows who I am either but that will soon
change as we bring more people and again
it's as I was saying before we went live
the purpose of these meetings is for us
to come together create a tech
cooperative that we all own meaning not
just the three of us not just however
many people are on camera but humanity
own so that they can trust it and see it
and we can transparently work through
this process of bringing something into
the world and part of that is creating a
meeting space that works for us is both
enjoyable and effective and working
through that - what you know what what
what is working about this and what is
it working in which will be easier in a
few weeks when we've been doing it for a
while but I will let you each introduce
yourselves I can go ahead and start
so Bentley Davis if you've been watching
they probably saw me on here last week
software developer and just looking for
ways to improve the world so I got some
ideas I was interested by jubblies idea
of a tech cooperative I'd had similar
ideas but not quite as well formed so
I'm just here to see what we can do to
move that idea forward so my name is
masala but for everyone's sake just
better to call me Jie Jie's just what
ever since I arrived in Australia I just
made everyone call me Jie I choose you
safe Stein so like everyone I've landed
in in the game game PE by accident and
it just sparked something in you we all
know what it is it's walking towards
there and we're gonna well nobody knows
when we're gonna get there but we're
gonna get there and so my project the
idea that I could come up with it's more
of all encompassing ideas more of like I
said an extension enhancing extension of
society
meant to help everyone transition into
game be slowly but surely my project
will take a little bit longer depending
on the type of support I'm gonna get but
the good thing about it is that it
doesn't really stop any other project
from moving forward because it's it's
meant to integrate everything even
though some might be affected it's it's
a lot of the stuff are out there already
people have worked on the little ideas
here and there that most of the theory
has already been thoughts most of the
technology has already been built it's
just a matter of us putting putting them
together in a rational civil organized
win-win way for all it's a bit difficult
to explain especially the first time and
being aware that this is live kind of
puts as well a little bit of added
pressure but makes you feel better G and
it's what every other game B people
who's awesome Ernesto he's doing Cuba
2.0 so it's not even like all the other
things it's not even the people who are
watching now it's the people who can be
watching later absolutely but just give
me a few minutes I'm usually like that
in the beginning of public speaking and
then I'll go out no problem like I said
this is our board meeting so we're gonna
be talking mainly about but I wanted
people to know who you are and what we
can also put a link to your project if
you have one in the description when I
well instead of calling board meeting
how about gate
there's gatekeepers because board
meeting like less than board I don't
like board meeting either I was calling
it like knights of the round table or so
me know it's like it's much more like
board meeting sounds very corporate and
very but gatekeepers sounds like we're
gatekeepers it sounds like you know what
I mean we're the ones becoming a new
hierarchy already like it doesn't even
to me its protectors of the values are
the way I mean visioning it in my
structure it's more that because
gatekeepers is a term being used around
game be conversations and since because
the way I'm visioning gatekeepers is
more in a way of they don't have any
following power they're known they can't
be known there's no way to not who they
are but they still keep watch to
preserve values
so there's decisions being made around
them that they don't well they just be
aware they study them try to think about
what the repercussions are yeah although
that that's a good concept I don't think
that's the purpose of this meeting no it
is that people know what a board meeting
is which is why board meeting works only
because people know what they're kind of
getting like it's us meeting to move the
project forward even if we're not yet
board members or there's not yet a board
or we want a later call it something
better than fix the world Friday or or a
board meeting Bentley I sent a link to
jewbilee just a while ago that I found
yesterday that there has some concepts
already built that we can actually use
to improve this tech cooperative because
if they've made the mistakes we can just
learn from them you know there's tons of
projects out there that are
amazing that are already doing the work
that's why we were discussing today I
believe you had done the document
Bentley the Google Talk and I wanted to
ask you why didn't just ask you this
week I don't know but asked you if you
wanted me to like add directly to that
or you wanted that to be kind of your
document and then like I was doing just
comments you know on the side or whether
you wanted it to be a collaborative
document yeah I think it's just a
collaborative document sometimes it is
hard to know when something was added I
guess I can go through the history the
other option is we can start adding our
comm are as adding our changes as you
know actual tracked changes in the
document camera what Google Docs calls
it and then the other person could
approve it but that still only works for
two people so maybe maybe we'll just go
ahead and yeah just go and start editing
it directly and if I get curious of what
you added there's a history option where
I can look and see yeah change last
having another document that's the
agenda for these weeks right either of
us has an idea just go and put it on
there during the week and then before
like if we're one of us like we're not
talking about that then whatever we can
put that next to it like I'm not ready
to or there's a reason why we're not
talking about that or we just put them
in order and then you know yeah yeah so
this is just kind of a brain dump at a
central place we could get all that
stuff and then yeah call out kind of
what do we want to talk about each week
because this is way more what I typed in
is way more than we could do in one week
yeah you just can make comments on any
you post you making the document with
the date you make the the the new adds
to the document and that's going to be
easier to track mm-hmm and it might be
easier to attract like I know the game
be document that was put up after I read
it through I was like well how am I
gonna know if there's new stuff at it
like I read it it's done right it's like
it might be in a published book they're
not changing things in it which is I
guess the difference between like a live
document yeah yeah there is but in you
know there are in if you using Google
Docs they have a they have a history the
thing in there and if you're putting
dates next to it that that doesn't
really work too well because you need to
put the com
in the correct section so you'd have to
still scroll through the whole document
to see when the changes were made so I
think their change tracking is probably
sufficient the best way to handle all
right now hmm it's just when it gets too
many people it might get complicated to
try Kappa yeah it will but right now
we're like I'm this is not my suit
they're like how to communicate that's
why I was like I can show up for an hour
meeting and have a conversation but like
the in-between part of being able to
communicate effectively I feel like that
is something we need tools for there are
tools out there but they're all paid
there are tools out there but like they
don't have quite the thing you need when
you're working on a not-for-profit or
your work you know on you know something
to have the funds to to back it and but
that's part of the process is doing what
we can do with the tools we have with
intellect we have right like you know
how to do that Bentley like I'd also
know how to use Google Talk like I don't
know why I'm discounting like I do use
them all the time but like once you use
them with someone else my brains like
wait how do like arnesto has an amazing
document on Cuba 2.0 but it's in Spanish
and English in my brain I'm like I I'm
like I want these to be side-by-side
English and Spanish so you can tell that
they're translated but like Google's not
just doing that they're not you don't
have een because if you then add
something in Spanish then it's not there
in English like I get why you need
interconnected but I think they're not
Ernesto
when is sort Marcus leeeeee gonna
implement a decent collaborative
document feature on face oh actually
that's not true
Club they might do that they might do
Google Docs because they're in
competition but it could be for
collaboration really there's already
some cool collaboration software out
there that's free actually it's called
one of them that I found it's really
interesting is called annotate penalty
yeah it's been using being used by
colleges and in like between teachers
and students it's like a a little plugin
you put it in chrome oh I'll check it
out see if it
yeah it's a it seems quick by Coolidge
and I haven't really used it but it
seems quite good and had scientists but
I've actually considered actually
reaching out to them because they're
they're very much in line with game be
objectives we said there's lots of
technology out there that's amazing it's
just until we have something to bring
them on board to either yours or mine or
any project there's it's like hey come
give us what you created when there's no
nothing to give it to and nothing like
we're not offering something and they
have something until there's a way to
bring those people together and say hey
what can we all offer each other right
how can all of these media ops that are
amazing and aren't owned by Twitter and
Facebook and Google but all don't have
the people in them and so they go by the
wayside like I just signed up for the
one you sent me which is called next
door sounds really cool and it's like a
personal I it was one of the ideas I had
for a like local Facebook right where
you're just talking to your neighbors so
you know if you need to know your cat if
you need I mean basically what I have a
cohousing but for every neighborhood and
so they verify not only your phone but
they're actually are sending me
something in the mail to verify and then
I have to find nine neighbors to join up
luckily my kids started at the local
school so I think I can do that but I'm
like what I can do knock on doors like
that's too much active somebody but the
fact that I've already signed up for
three of these this is my skirt one it
was a neighborhood Facebook that I've
signed up for we have the threshold of
people this is the first one who tells
me to find I neighbors though and I
think that's an important piece is that
you did they're the best ones out there
but they still have a few flaws already
that I saw in their concept mostly
privacy privacy there they're throwing
it out the door even worse than Facebook
well that's you don't have to know your
neighbors are part of it you have to
know your neighbors names not details
right I'm not on it yet so I literally I
just you can research a few other videos
like it's been on the news and I found
like other like private eyes as well
saying if you issue that that might
arise
from the way it's built and that all
comes down to identity and privacy which
is let me let me focus us back on on the
topic which we don't have yet we talked
briefly last week I wanted to and then
let's let's create an agenda is there
anything you would like all the agenda
Bentley so yeah I threw a lot of stuff
out on the brainstorming doc I'm trying
to figure out which one I think is the
most important I think you know yeah
coming up with agenda this most
important thing I guess what I would ask
is if you've kind of glanced through
this I would like to hear either things
that you think are top priority which I
think we want to I think one of the top
things is kind of like looking through
the possible projects and seeing where
we want to start I'm still kind of
leaning towards idea cafe but and then
you know anything I wrote in here that
that you found concerning and I think it
would be good for us to chat through
that yeah no I think that's great I'm
also wondering why I didn't already have
it up when we started you emailed it to
me right yeah there we go brainstorming
okay it's now up and going I haven't
read it through it I had read through it
when you sent it to me
and then so possible projects one of the
issues is just that yes I have dozens of
ideas for projects I don't know if we
need all ideas for projects more if
there's one like I think there were
three I had mentioned and if you want to
add any that are like potential first
projects even the three that I've
mentioned honestly the labor one
although unless there's more people
involved it's really hard to start a
labor platform even though it comes with
its own funding source but having a
third option so we can compare them and
say here's why we would choose this one
and not choose this one here's why we
would you know for them if there's
another one that you think is the three
were the idea Cafe which is a
communications platform the labor
platform which gives us money and also a
lot of people right away anyone who
wants to earn money anyone who wants to
hire someone the third one was the
Yelp platform right creating which keeps
coming up in this in this space is all
of these cool projects are out there how
do we bring them together how do we
offer them something how do we share
trust among them so every new project
isn't starting from Ground Zero against
the big tech giants even if they're not
game B right even if I don't know who
owns next door I don't know if I can
trust them I don't know anything but
creating the thing to know who owns it
where does the money come from where
does it go how trustworthy is it how do
I communicate with them so we can make
it better right like creating something
that helps that communication tool is to
me a very powerful place to start
because it shows us all of the places
where our next project could be but also
the idea cafe is extremely important
having a place to communicate with a
large group of people it's not going to
work on YouTube but using zoom using
very beta type technology to be able to
bring people together and say when are
you available one of the questions we're
asking let's have a conversation about
it once you bring humanity together and
give them real connection it solves a
lot of problems overnight and from that
space it branches out fast accessory
when they have the tools to be able to
collaborate and when they create a
project has the Yelp this is the issue
is like every project feeds off the
other ones it's like first one because I
want this one so that it interacts with
these ones and so right so that's we're
still study the agenda so I get off
track so discussing project so that like
having less so we're talking about the
document so that was one of the things
was just there's a lot of projects which
are awesome I think that's great but but
focusing it down to ones that are I've
also just in my mind this is not a
because everyone's mind works
differently I've been putting my
projects in like three categories like
one is information like history the
history one and the science one and
politics one I love a lot of which have
already been done but need to be doesn't
be out the other one is community ones
like the idea cafe and the third one are
platforms which are kind of the
combination of the other two like how we
bring I don't know I honestly anyway
building testable person yeah I just I
researched
few documents to try and get better
organizing my project then so that I
found a really interesting document that
helped me organize some of the problems
and how I would review their importance
and so the characteristics they're
saying - for me to look for our popular
a lot of people have the problem growing
problems that are growing fast that more
people will be engaged in as time goes
on from there are urgent problems that
are expensive those will get you
investors problems that are mandatory
people like I have it I have this
problem I have to solve it now and
problem problems that are frequent so
basically those would be the game be
knows what uh there are lots of problems
we have lots of problems and they all
need to be solved simultaneously and
have feedback loops so we can kind of
like deal with the we make as we
make it yeah yeah but from the idea what
I'm saying is from the ideas you've had
applied these terms yeah and see what
comes out on top yeah so several metrics
kind of points you towards the game a
space and we're developed in game a so
we have to be careful I would so some of
those I would take off and I would add a
couple this is just a reference it's
just a guy here's Ernesto's option for
the first one which I love but I don't
know if it helps with our game be space
but immigrant human empowerment platform
and I think that any like any platform
that brings people together to be able
to form their own groups even if like
and that our group is one of those
groups is also powerful but again you
need the people like it's like you need
people you need funding you need like
all these things to come together and
some projects bring one and not the
other and other projects and so figuring
out how we fund the first project how we
create we have a crazy things and so
back to the dock
the only other so there's a few things
here that just aren't my aren't my
wheelhouse which is awesome that they
are yours Bentley which is like the
rolls I'm like I don't know but yeah
yeah absolutely right which is important
but also creating this in a way that
like if we don't have money we can't
hire people so we kind of have to deal
with who comes on board right like which
doesn't not to do that because it's like
right if we wanted graphic designer
let's put that out in the universe let's
ask where's the graphic designer someone
watching might know when they might be
one but we can only be so yeah yeah yeah
and so finding this seems to work in
this space the right people come around
at the right time which is awesome the
only issue I had with the whole document
Bentley was and it's not really an issue
why do I use that language but the
community rules which I under totally
understand you just took from the game
be space the Facebook group yeah as a
starter place even when they did it I
was like wait how did you guys have a
three-person conversation and then put
it up and decide that I don't have a
problem with a single one of these
community rules except that they exist
meaning that like any set of rules any
set of guidelines starts with it like
explain us like it starts with the
premise that these things are already
gonna go wrong and it also starts the
premise like if you can't do this you
can't be part of this group which I
understand the importance of it at the
same time as somebody who's had brain
damage so that I don't have as much will
powers I used to have I don't have
enough certain things that other people
do I get how everyone can't be this like
everyone doesn't have the same access to
emotional intelligence or locus or those
kind of things and so although I have no
problem with any of those to me like
simple rules like be kind and try you
don't be like try to show up and do
those things are simpler like even the
Omega rule which I like is like everyone
wait but like it's too complicated for
people that kind of understand and it's
not that I don't think there should be
guidelines I think there needs to be
more of us before there's guidelines and
right now when there's really just two
of us Bentley and I and then like Jesus
joining us today it would be like how do
we
like what are our guidelines to interact
with each other right and then when a
third person comes on board what do they
need as opposed to making these
overarching how do we like those are
important things to discuss if that
makes sense but not necessarily have as
like law when I want as little law as
possible have it be more simple be kind
and when you mess up on mess-up make an
apology make it amends figure out like
even that is hard for a lot of people so
how does somebody do that it doesn't
have the skill right can we walk someone
through an apology like this is
literally how you do an apology and them
yeah yeah well be be kinds a bit more
advanced than I mean apology is a bit
more advanced than because right so yeah
I've seen someone some of the comments
on the Facebook about simple rules and I
agree with that in theory and I agree I
like your eye I'm not opposed the idea
of saying let's not have any until more
of a community comes about so yeah so
any I guess anything I'm thinking could
be discussed then it's like building
this organically is like if you do
something that annoys me whether it's on
camera or not right like if it there's
something that we can discuss that and
we can figure that out
does it need like I don't know what that
conflict would be I have very little
conflict in my life but um like then we
deal with it and we go okay well is
something that's gonna happen in the
future right it was in a
misunderstanding was it like how can
there be like a rule in place either
overarching or for us that would help
that not happen in the future
like how did dealing with stuff as it
comes up not ignoring that it's going to
possibly happen but not having to think
of everything it could possibly happen
and recreating a new game without
creating it like under game age dynamics
is a very different way right it's like
okay well how do two people work
together how do three people work
together how do four people work
together including that this might take
off right away and there might be a
hundred of us right away right like
owning that it's gonna be uncomfortable
owning that this is a new space to be in
at least for me like I've in my mind
figured out game B but now I've got to
figure it out with other people and
that's exciting and fun
and it's also gonna rub up against my
ego right and against Lake hmm all that
stuff and yours too I'm guessing I think
everyone has ego and and that level of
things and how we make everybody happy
how we actually create a world that
works for everyone doesn't work if we're
not creating a world that works for us
right and so it's creating this
microcosm of an hour that works for us
that is how do we have an agenda put
forward
how do we keep on topic how do we let it
go and have fun and and and figure out
how to communicate between sessions that
works right that is something that like
I said I can show up for an hour and I'm
Friday okay that in between let me take
a step back you had three sections for
your potential projects you said
community platforms what was the third I
missed one of them information so like
yeah information information community
and then like like platforms meeting
services right like things that are more
like Airbnb and where they don't own the
houses but they connect you and so
actual things that are built from the
ground up but we don't necessarily own
the food but we're connecting people to
find their food and co-op and buy it
together and start projects and do yeah
communities like kind of the underlining
tools of how to do all that and also
just people need people and how do we
facilitate that for everyone
everyone's deserving of people even if
they're not deserving of me as a people
or you don't be like we don't mesh I
still want to help them find people
because I know that or better or better
with others so yeah I think our kind of
three main goals would be or several
goals would be you know building tools
that we could use in building together
tech which idea cafe would you don't
definitely be one of those both
internally and use for other things and
then you talked about you know of some
sort of tool that would more easily
provide some sort of funding like the
labor skills training system I think
you're right in saying that that's a
rather big project it would be difficult
for the
first one all my other ideas that I kind
of threw in there were just small helper
tools none of them have a good I think
are great for funding some of them I
think we could use in our decision
process but we probably don't need them
yet like I think it'd be nice if we had
a little prioritization tool Tory you
know we could each prioritize these
projects off loans
I don't need then like voting kind of to
say this is the one I think or later but
simplest and this one's the cheapest and
this one like raking them for ranked
choice voting yeah have you used travel
before yes Trello doesn't have a right
choice voting option
it just has a single prioritization
level yeah it doesn't this has a
proposition you can put the tests on
there for a single person yeah not
people prioritization I'm pretty sure
the game beat page has won the trouble
or each individual person can prioritize
each task in a Trello board for
themselves yeah for themselves No
yeah because the idea is to kind of vote
on it right to say that make a group
decision leave a small enough group here
that no fools are necessary which is I
mean this is what I've been working on
us for three years I started in
groundswell and the people who I love
for concie like pick a project and get
people on board I'm like that's not I'm
not doing that because it keeps cycling
but like when there's a second person
and we pick a project I will stick to it
so I think thinking through this through
and talking through it I would like to
go ahead and take the steps down towards
exploring idea cafes as the first
project and then if we kind of hit a
wall you know then we can we can
reassess but that would probably be my
preference plus I have some ideas on
some technology we may be able to use
and it it may not be very difficult to
implement depending
your ideas and what you know what we may
add to it well let's take a step farther
than YouTube yes so um I don't know if I
told you last week how I kind of came to
the idea cafe and that it was a World
Cafe format yeah you said it originally
came from World Cafe so I was wondering
how much and how much we want to does
does that format in their goals all fit
or is there anything that we need any
additional changes to make make it fit
our needs a little bit better from the
world for cafe format mm-hmm I mean the
World Cafe format is a real life tool
but they have now done online and I
participated in one finally online
they're actually changing I think they
are creating a platform to do the World
Cafe format but not necessarily quickly
and also using zoom I think like the
idea is zoom you can do breakout groups
we can't necessarily do more of the
second level algorithms stuff like if
two people don't get along how do we not
put them together because the more
people do we have to separate into
specific groups that's just creates way
too many complications if it's a
physical person doing it right the only
thing that doesn't work in theirs is
that they don't have to in the real
world ones they have the table clause to
keep notes and in the online version
they have a Google Doc that people just
kind of put put notes in it's just
chaotic for my brain but it's not even
necessarily that it doesn't work if we
were its the idea behind the idea cafe
the reason I'm using YouTube is because
I can write I could have a conversation
with a small amount of people and I
would love to have a beta version where
people can say when they're available
and then you can match them up on it on
it on a question and as a group we could
have a question per day that everyone
can answer and then the next day we're
harvesting that question if there's
enough of us I tried this in game B and
there were not enough of us to make it
work to work with all the time zones
because the idea is if we're global we
have to we can't have everyone meeting
at 11:00 a.m. on Friday right for G this
is this is what 5:00 a.m. your time I'm
almost 6 a.m.
which is not you know do it some other
place foster I believe it's even earlier
than that and so having a way to have an
effective conversation when we don't all
have to attend to say meeting but people
do feel like they're participating
because they are right this is an
important important piece that we want
to on as much as I'm calling this a
board meeting the less we can have us be
the central focus and have it more be
like we want everyone's ideas we want to
be able to do they use aggregate bode
not so that I get to decide what the
best thing is but like we get to decide
now if you and I are doing the labor
it's you and me that are deciding what
we're doing right it's not a third
person telling us what project we're
creating and then we're creating it when
we have a technology I'm getting off
topic are do we have a technology
company makes more sense to hire
employees and be like no this is what
you're creating create it but right now
when it's us and we're doing it for free
and we're choosing to do it we want to
do one we're passionate about right that
like call us to us and the idea cafe is
that because I think that when I first
thought about it I was like okay it's
gonna be just for together tech and
we're gonna have a question a day or a
question a day that brings humanity
forward and then once we that threshold
is met and that's workable we can then
start introducing a second topic maybe
people branch off into food creation and
talking about how you created it we
don't like that you're talking about
world-changing things but then having
the YouTube channel for together for
idea cafe we haven't been talking about
world-changing things mostly we've been
talking about things that are important
to me because they're things I want to
talk about about neurodiversity about
autism about about donor conception is
for the last the three of the ones that
we were talking about and I'm like how
powerful for anyone to be able to do
that because the feedback I have gotten
is that it's a fun experience to be able
to come and have kind of a shaped
conversation where you should everyone
shares for five minutes then you have a
bit of a conversation it connects you in
a way that current social media doesn't
and to be able to form groups from that
to be able to actually say hey I really
like Bentley I'd really like to work
with him in the future and just like
check it off right not necessarily have
to approach you and do that but like
cool look there's enough of you who've
all liked each other who can form groups
or have it be that we did get together
we had a really cool machine session and
like hey let's actually move forward
with this thing we created or it gets up
right we're the ones who create it maybe
it goes through that tablecloth whatever
we version we create become something
new or someone else the bigger group can
take it on that we upload it right it
becomes something that the larger group
can harvest and create together
yeah so I'm I'm thinking through that I
guess I hear a process and a technique I
don't know what what it can bring people
together which is a benefit but is that
the net result you know I or is the goal
to move us towards a game be space or is
it to move us towards the tech
cooperative I mean we can do all of
those things with that type of platform
but I think it'd be easier for me to
visualize if I knew what would hope to
get out of it specifically so for us I
think and this is the original you stop
me if I get off-topic cuz I will I
always know that the original vision
like I said was so that it would help
together attack so it was one question a
day and it was how do we get the people
involved to be part of that question
right how do we ask hey what is the
first if we already had it ready what's
our next project so then maybe we have a
we don't know so we have a conversation
what would the Yelp wouldn't look like
what would this one look like how would
that impact your life right whatever the
question is it's an idea cafe question
when we don't know the answer to one
that's open-ended hopefully almost
anyone can answer and it moves us
forward right because it's thousands of
people or hundreds of people having a
conversation to get people to be part of
that conversation look I don't know if
people would be on Facebook if the point
of Facebook was to run Facebook right so
having people be part of it so they can
have conversations about addiction about
becoming parents about like doing things
that are important to them and then some
of those people are gonna choose to be
part of the bigger conversation about
the tech cooperative and how we move it
forward and how we improve it
and then an even smaller group of those
people are gonna want to harvest those
conversations to be part of the next one
sorry my hands are all my face I'll
colored from Halloween yesterday did I
answer the question Bentley of what it's
more yeah I think though we need to so
yeah I'm trying to decide so for if
we're just doing the idea cafe as the as
the main idea and not just have the idea
cafe be a source I mean at the same time
we could use idea cafe to bootstrap
together tech as far as you know
building the organization we could do
both I guess what I'm thinking is I
couldn't Cafe be the first up I'm more
thinking the other way around
I mean it would be yes but I guess what
I'm saying is that together tech would
also be one of the first idea cafes but
I can wait
yeah just that my preference would be
that we try and start off with building
idea cafe to build together tech because
I think if it's just an open thing
saying hey we want people to the end
result is that people talk more I feel
like that's not going to be as effective
sorry I was reading what Nestor said and
I missed the last 30 seconds what you
said Bentley um I apologize I mind can't
seem to do two things at once it's
challenging
yeah I was just saying that that my
preference would be that we would kind
of focus using idea cafe to build
together tack into the together tech to
build idea cafe yeah I think to your
point about people wouldn't be a whole
bunch of people wouldn't be on Facebook
if it was about building Facebook but
Facebook wasn't a a community platform I
think if it was you'd have a lot of
people saying hey
build this video platform how do we want
to build it we're gonna use video to
talk about it so I think in this case is
a little bit easier to have them
building each other I
great idea badly so or that I was
actually kind of writing notes about it
was like I need just I hate that I want
to interrupt people when I have an idea
as opposed to like being able to hold it
and then wait but I'll get better at
that
so for the idea of the the labor
platform as well as the Yelp for apps
both of those would work way better if
we had idea cafe up and running right
because the idea of platform is is the
labor platform is that we get a bunch of
uber drivers together we get a bunch of
air whatever it is and we ask like what
works about it what doesn't work about
it right like having conversations that
maybe I'm not I've never been an uber
driver I wouldn't know how to be part of
that but facilitating that so we can
learn how we can learn what they need
from anyone right and they can be part
of creating that so even if they don't
want to be a member of the cooperative
they still want to have it an app that
they would use as a driver right
same with for the apps like getting a
bunch of app developers together insane
what has worked for projects what is the
like what does it cost you that people
don't trust you why did it go out of
business right like asking questions
that bring them together to be part of
creating that is does that make sense so
like creating it so that the beta
version is about like we don't
necessarily need a bunch of host
cleaners to be on board to create it we
can actually reach out when we have the
tech and say hey we're house cleaners we
want a bunch of you to get together so
you can create some amazing for
yourselves right and then invite those
people on board and then they're there
theoretically and if we're sending out
emails to people I mean hey this is the
new one right baby you're a house
cleaner at an uber driver and now we're
talking to our drivers and you don't
even think we're sending it out and the
more information you give the more we're
gonna be able to help you have
conversations that matter
and we're also drawing in people who are
here to create something better
right like you said about Facebook where
that wasn't a point of Facebook and that
is the point of what we're creating so a
few things that I've just found here so
seems like WordPress already has
some voting plugins and they're
basically free sites so we can easily
build this for free at least with the
blogging voting forum kind of thing
that's I'm not really sure exactly what
they have I'm sure we can create an
initial platform to at least centralize
information with some sections with
tools to use or not sure the features
that you you want to have on on the cafe
initially I'm pretty sure that this this
specific video conference might not be
present on WordPress but we can just
organize there and then use this as a
side tool for now until we can integrate
something I don't are you are either a
few familiar with WordPress I have
somebody else making a very basic basic
WordPress site for together tech and
even that is unlike WordPress I'm a web
designer I've done designed web design I
do computers and all that so and I've
actually I haven't really gone into it
but it should be pretty simple I've been
a web developer for 20 years so when
I've been doing WordPress for a couple
years both front end and back end but
before we kind of jump onto that my
preference would be that we kind of
figure out what's what what our needs
are because actually I mean gee I
mentioned voting and stuff is one of the
additional projects but I'm not sure
that that's a need within within idea
cafe or not yet so what I'd like to do
is either I mean maybe not maybe or
maybe not today but it's one of those
I'm the only one who can't what what I'd
like to do then is us step through so
far your idea of game be and what and
maybe whatever G and I kind of think is
necessary
and talked through those requirements
for lack of a better word so that we can
kind of start flushing out that idea
like what game B means to us no I'm
sorry did I say game B I mean I
completely I have the tab up so idea
cafe I'm so I was in annoyingly minut
detail of what what features we need in
order for you know maybe even the big
idea cafe and then we can pare it back
down to what's our V of course you're
already doing V one with YouTube right
so what's a one point five right so yeah
just kind of start listing out those
features so we can either start that now
or if there's any other topics she'll
wanna so yeah absolutely let's start
that so having a scheduler like
something where I can say when I'm
available and it can tell me other
people who are available or to back-end
that like we're sorry to reverse that
having like I tried in game B space to
say okay well there's I tried it so
would be every four hours there'd be six
conversations a day so people would be
available for multiple ones in their own
in their number time zone they were in
hopefully it could be two a day right
one at 4:00 a.m. one at 4:00 p.m. and so
that's either 5 6 p.m. 6 a.m. like
starting beta and creating bigger right
so eventually it gets to the point where
the idea Cafe originally was going to be
a 24 hour conversation so that you could
come on and have a half an hour chunk
conversation at any hour or half an hour
mark and you'd participate in multiple
ones because that's also part of what
the World Cafe is is it's not you just
you come on necessarily be part of one
conversation but you bring that same
conversation to the next one to the next
one and so like the world's kind of
having a conversation around the world
and around time zones about a question
and then it flips over the next day and
some of those people go in to harvest
the question which is just having a
conversation exactly like the idea cafe
that happened the day before but about
what was the commonality right like just
what did we get out of that what was
what was her
like just I can't even think of the
questions you would ask but finding the
thread the common thread what was alive
for you what was you know like having
multiple conversations the next day on
that one and I don't think everyone
would do that every day I'd be like if
that one was really alive for you is
when you're gonna go on board the next
day and if one isn't it all right no one
wants to harvest it then it wasn't that
great of a conversation that did it cool
right like right so how many how many
people did it normally say generally in
a group set forth well to have a table
it's three to five people I found for
the idea cafe works well a series
actually magic like I really like the
three because there's more time to talk
and more time to share and there's
enough it's better than two five is like
too much if you're having a half an hour
conversation you'll take five minutes to
share there isn't enough time to kind of
have a little bit of a conversation for
is what the World Cafe talks about but
no nerd to be able to switch groups on
the World Cafe at twelve peoples is the
minimum to have a World Cafe so that
people are sitting at a table and they
move to a different table they move to a
different table yeah with the 24/7
format that's doesn't really apply it's
just people breaking off into three or
four in the game of beef space there
weren't enough people to even have one
group right let alone like there was not
a time where we had to break out into
breakout groups because I was trying to
have six conversations a day and there's
like a few hundred people in game B
right yeah so when I think of the
scheduler depending on how complex we
want to make it it could be to where
people go in just state sometimes that
they're free and then rather than having
it at like four times a day although you
could definitely do it that way is that
it would just find a time that's common
between in any time there's four people
it could then group them together
although I guess even if you have two or
three people maybe it could post the
time and then other people can choose to
join anyways but maybe you supposed to
be you know four times a day is is
probably easier for people to grapple
with or available slots and then when
the slot gets four people and it three
to four people and then
then it would you know schedule at for
them ya know I like I like that process
like I said it kind of growing out both
starting with like one question a day
where it isn't more than one question
and then as we grow when there's
millions of us we can have dozens of
questions writing you can pick which one
to talk about in your area of interest
but when there's only a few hundred of
us or even only a few thousand of us we
actually can we need to focus on like
one or two questions not will say even
even a day I wonder if we could take out
the time limit and just say you know
these are the next five questions so if
that if a group of four comes about then
they're assigned the first question or
actually the first four groups right or
assign the first question three groups
three groups assign the first question
and then you have a a round of what were
you talking about where you take a look
at the notes and everything
yeah harvesting so yeah so in order
because you don't just want one group
read having a one meeting about one
question right you want to have multiple
groups meeting about the same question
yeah so the World Cafe works in
generally two ways they have the same
conversation again and again so they
have the same question you are
participating and answering it at
different tables with different people
or it can be one question and then a
slightly built on question and another
built on question right so what is the
one for the World Cafe which has been
pretty common is like tell us about a
hosting experience you've had right it
could be like hosting your family over
to your house hosting a conversation and
then I don't know what the second one is
the last one's like what's a
conversation you would like to have like
where would you like to post and how did
that hosteen affect you or what did you
need to effectively host there's like
it's all on kind of the World Cafe like
how do you effectively have a
conversation and it's still different
every month based on who shows up to be
part of that conversation and that's
kind of the same thing but we're also
trying to bring it into technology right
which is like some of questions don't
quite work for a World Cafe format but
nor should they and we can adopt it be
like right
is a more technical question but we need
to ask some and even even since we're
more a asynchronous you know because we
don't all have to be in the same space
at the same time yeah so I was thinking
maybe a stream of questions like five
questions and then you whenever you have
a meeting you would have meeting about
question one and then if you choose to
have another meeting and other people
are available that have already done
question one then you could be put in a
meeting to do question two might be a
way to say disentangle it from the
timing the other thing I like about that
is that um for people entering the space
right for the first time to not
understand what's been going on and then
be jumped into it is a little abrupt
especially through like hey all this
stuff happen we need a way to con it to
so many of that anyway to everyone to be
able to say hey this is the entry level
questions right this is like you go
through these twelve questions when we
have enough people and then you get to
join the rest of the group right like
having a more of like a initiation to
see you're caught up to speed to be like
this is what it's like to be part of a
conversation right to know if this is
for you to know if this type of
conversation is gonna add to your life
and you're gonna add to it which is less
important if you adds to your life
you're adding to it there's kind of no
in-between but if you hate this format
not gonna work for you or anyone you're
participating right yeah so the first
question could be a softball one that
also helps them understand the process
yeah exactly
like what's the plan I know to work as
we as you intended don't you need some
game peeing fluid game being influenced
people already in those groups to kind
of guide the conversation or or else
they just fall into game a traps all
over again possibly but the questions
are designed to not do that like the
questions are that's where it's
different than a debate format it's not
like do you believe in climate change
which we could agree with or not agree
with its how is climate change impacted
your life you can't agree or disagree
with that like you can say I don't
believe in it it's wrecked my life I've
worked in the oil fields and now I'm
unemployed that's valid I can say hey my
home
let it you know what I mean those are
valid answers there's no wrong about it
even if it triggers the other person
it's not even question in a way that
brings out people that would they do the
World Cafe they spend a lot of time
reiterating the World Cafe like every
time there's like an hour I swear at the
beginning which I get really annoyed
with in case you can't so I'm like why
are we do like why isn't there a
five-minute video everyone has to watch
before they come on like here's how you
participate right you each take turn you
have a talking stick and you don't
interrupt each other which I can do and
this talking stick one of the things
part of it like I will talk next and
it's a spin like and I'm passing it off
to Australia and then she would pick one
like mine it would be great if there was
an actual like virtual talking stick to
be like I'm talking yeah and well in the
system I mean the microphones could be
off for everybody except for the person
talking instead and then it could it
could you know randomly go to the next
person and tell them you know somehow
identify who has that so I just listed
as a feature a training video I did G I
did put in your just question about do
we need a moderator can they fall in the
game a I think jublee your points are
perfect I just want to keep that thought
around for a little while longer
I wasn't trying to dismiss it outright
and be like never but like we have
hundreds of people to have like 200 if
we have a thousand people to have 250
hosts is too much but there might be a
possibility to be like hey these people
have had 10 conversations honorary host
yeah so how so you have the problem
there so we have it's too many hosts you
think people won't be motivated for so
what you need to find is find a way to
motivate people to be housed a value
that that you can distribute to people
if they participates in a more active
way in that they can use it for
something some sort of
[Music]
credit maybe across the other platform
across you can move the credit you gain
in this in the cafe or other apps across
the the tech cooperative and then you
can use the same and that is not
necessarily a currency it's just
something to have value because you a
currency will need to be used outside
the platform and this is just inside so
it's kind of is not you know yeah yeah I
think I'm gonna consider if we if we if
we find we need moderators and we find
out it's hard to get them exactly I mean
yeah if you don't need incentive we
don't I think it's it's for me and this
is just my feeling and it'll be more
less about incentivizing them to get
something outside and more about finding
the people who are good at that and that
is their like I love moderating awesome
I love being like there are people with
such great motional intelligence and
they can guide the conversation and do
that and it's part of who they are that
you almost can't train and therefore
like the issue is getting those people
at individual tables and the an
algorithm can do that right hey these
people are really great do you mind us
splitting you up like you might not be
with another one and being the person
who can who can do that and and offering
them that right being like wow you're
amazing at this and side like that is at
least part of the vision of together
tech is helping people find what they're
good at and that you don't have to pay
them when they find their passion like
when they find what they're here to do
on this planet they will do it for free
all day every day you just have to give
them the tools to do that I'm not one of
those people who necessarily wants to
host but I love being part of a
conversation and so I've effectively had
kind of had to become a host so that I
can host my own conversation because I
have and that is the hardest part about
idea cafe for me is getting people
together in the same space right being
like I can generate questions I can even
pick the communities but actually like
putting it out there and having people
take the bait and then scheduling it and
then like if the tech can do that and
that's where the motivation kicks in the
motivation is more of a something to
bring people in because if if the
concept is built correctly it's not the
motive
that keeps them in the motivation just
brings them in and then they enjoy the
experience and then they're just all
into the experience that's pretty much
which I think it's a very important part
of the entire experience right that's
why I was like what makes this what
makes this process fun and are like
enjoyable and productive because if it's
not enjoyable we're not gonna keep
coming back week after week and if it's
not productive we can keep coming back
week after week but nothing's done and
it'll be a similar conversation for idea
cafe right of like what made this fun
what would make it better what we which
is what I'm trying to do off of YouTube
is like right what not just what made it
fun for me but what made what would make
it more fun and that is where I'm like
three people is actually really cool for
sharing your story and then having a
conversation on YouTube in that format
it doesn't necessarily work for more but
we're not trying to solve anything we're
trying to share a story and it's
different for different pieces of it and
that's why I'm glad I'm not a coder
because I would have coded it and it
would have been wrong it would have been
like this is for me to have a
conversation and then realize it's not
what it needs to be it needs to be able
to change in iterate which is the beauty
of technology is it can so we mentioned
note-taking during the meeting do you
think that just something like a Google
Doc or uh I can't remember there's a
couple tech that works the same way is
sufficient or you mentioned that that's
tough for you is there anything else
that would make that easier no we'd have
to create it from scratch for it to be
something I think that works the best I
mean a bit of it release it for now
allowing that we are the document right
like a part of the idea cafe and the
World Cafe is that you're the one who's
bringing that knowledge to the next
group you're the piece that changed to
bring it to the next conversation and
then harvesting it and getting those
things to be in a way there will be
people who their passion is diagramming
right and those people might need to get
paid those people might need the
incentive because there might be I don't
know how what percentage of the
population they are they might not want
to harvest and documents right and it's
finding the more you need people to be
one and the other
it's harder to find people but having
people right like if we need a
documentary because those documentaries
that need to get together and kind of
figure out how to make one thing that we
can
right out to ever and be like this is
what that conversation generated right
this is how we like build on it from one
to the next but the bigger piece is
we're the build on from one to the next
how did you grow what did you learn and
how do you bring that to your next
conversation and so if we that's so
let's leave it without that let's talk
about it without having any sort of
document I'd like to explore that a bit
then do we need in order for the
knowledge to grow and spread do we need
to have a group like if we take four
groups and switch everyone around tour
no one's with anyone they had before do
they need to actually talk about the
same question or a very similar question
so that the information gets shared and
built the idea is yes because then
you're part of the same conversation
like then you can kind of know that
other people are having that same
conversation and then you know that even
if you weren't part of that you're you
both had a similar conversation you're
then bringing in to the next one and
saying hey like you're also bringing
that into it literally like hey so what
so and so said this that resonates with
this right like you're you're actually
physically like I might take notes right
I might take my own notes to be able to
understand it myself and I bring those
with me to the next table and it World
Cafe format there is a host who is
taking notes and they stay they stay at
the table so that one person physically
is there all the time and everyone else
rotates around that's not really virtual
doesn't work that way because it's yeah
it's just not how it zoom works well we
need to let the conversation evolve even
because they can you can start with a
question and that question can easily
lead to something else that's
extraordinary and doesn't really relate
to the initial question after three or
four groups had their meetings and the
conversation has completely evolved
somewhere else that is a very game B
space which has been awesome like with
the wormhole group where it was like hey
like someone would talk I think it was
like 15 of us on the call and the next
person would just start from that point
it was really cool but
know how it moves forward it's like the
idea is to be able to have a
conversation with thousands or even
millions of people around the world in
different time periods where you feel
like you were part of something because
you all had the same conversation even
if it was with different people and then
you're generating a new question that
that might evolve into right like oh
that brings up this question I would
love to discuss and then you're
submitting that and voting on it to see
whether you all want to talk like
whichever question kind of resonates the
most with you yeah so if you have so
imagine that during the wormhole someone
talks about because the idea is you
don't interrupt other people so somebody
is talking about something that you feel
important you create a tag on that
second of the video that in the end of
the wormhole
everyone goes backs watches the tags
tries to extrapolate the actual idea
into a document let's say and then you
can look at all the other things that
got pulled out of the of the
conversation try to organize them in
some way in that funnels out into the
other conversations that's good idea let
me take a quick step back though for the
automated talking stick for the talking
stick what are what were the rules on
that is it five minutes per person no
that was the idea cafes I don't think
you just cuz you're in for people you
know you have 20 minutes so you want to
make sure everyone has a chance to talk
they generally let you go till you're
done but like there are people who will
talk for 20 minutes and there are people
who will talk for 30 seconds there are
people that don't want to talk and I
think it's the idea cafe it's it's
because you're answering a question and
the people don't know each other it's
like you literally just answer that
question and take turns and then you
have a brief conversation again which
seems to be an enjoyable experience and
it's easy to understand right it's like
you talk for five minutes and you're
done you're good
the next person talks and it's even and
then you can monopolize or in monopolize
in the last last part of it when you
were thinking through this what was your
thought on is there a process that you
of the five minutes but that's cuz
that's how my mind works I don't
interrupt people when they have five
minutes and I do when we're in a
conversation despite like having rules
for my brain but that doesn't mean that
has to be the iteration well so yeah but
I kind of like that idea as well
and I almost but I do like having an
open discussion period I don't know five
minutes I mean I'm almost thinking like
I mean and and of course we can flex
these numbers as much as we want but
like three minutes per person and then a
10 20 minute a 10 minute group
discussion which I don't know if made us
not long enough the idea was for them to
be half an hour total so that this 24
hour conversation but that's if we're
starting with for time period like you I
saying so for certain questions half an
hour's not enough in five minutes isn't
enough when we're telling our life
stories and we're telling about like our
brain tumors story five minutes isn't
enough
and then the conversation also isn't
enough it's like no forever when you're
talking about something that's more
emotional and more like you I don't know
it would just feel like a long time to
talk for five minutes I think it's very
topic dependent and we'll have to find
the sweet spot for people talking about
the topics we're choosing to move idea
cafe and the next project their tech
forward and maybe just these I mean I do
think it's good to have a max time like
you said because some people find it
difficult to regulate and then so and
then yeah that's that number of the
number of minutes we can we can actually
not something just came up to when
you're talking about that so imagine
this you have the five minutes but it's
more of a guide the person starts
talking the five minutes are up the
other people involved in in the
discussion receives and for a visual
warning that tells them that the person
has already talked for five minutes and
let them decide if they're in if they're
talking about something interesting or
it's just going down the drain so this
week yeah and if they're finding
something interesting they
won't do anything if they see that
they're going off-topic or something
like that they'll just press a button
that puts out the signal and the person
talking starts seeing some sort of graph
growing and and it will come to their
attention see okay I need to stop
talking I've gone off track or whatever
yeah I mean I think that's valid there
are times where that's absolutely you're
like this person needs to share more
they are like I'm cutting them off see
me not help we need to be very mindful
that this conversation is is the goal we
need to cherish conversation like this
is the format I've done it in and so I
would come on like I would have just you
up on the screen when you're talking and
then I would come back on you would know
your five minutes is up but I would let
you finish
stop talking mid-sentence I thought
about that one but just in in in the in
the brain of a person as soon as you see
someone else appearing it could cancel
the idea in their head break the
conversation yeah and by doing it like I
was saying it it doesn't send any signal
to the person who's actually talking and
only it allows the other person the
other people who have more mind space to
handle that because my issue with that
would be only some people know when
they've talked for five minutes right
like so because we all are very bad at
guesstimating when we've talked for five
minutes some of us are gonna talk over
five minutes just not knowing we hit
five minutes and some of us are going to
wait underestimate and stop at two
minutes thinking we used up our five
minutes and so just based on whether
you're an under overestimate or you're
gonna get more or less time to talk and
so knowing that like like here there's a
counter on the screen that says my voice
starts maybe there's a counter I mean I
would love in a later version to
actually able to see my metrics right to
be able to say hey you wouldn't
authorize that conversation right
where's right now let's just do I think
I monopolize it I suppose - how much is
actually monopolized it shouldn't be
that hard to make and yeah I think you
that time we're definitely
has a place there so do we still want to
have a unregulated group discussion time
or do you think it should always be a
talking stick oh no all right because
that's part of it it's like when the
magic happens been like you say
something I say something we share and
then it's like the after part of like
the first idea cafe I had was a was on
911 and we were sharing our 911 stories
and me and my friend I've known for
forever have acquaintances more and she
talked about being in Greece and not
speaking the language and she's from
Britain and I was in Australia when it
happens and I spoke the language but we
both had this experience of travelling
into a foreign country in one world and
traveling out in another world and the
third person who'd already agreed to be
part of it for it was even about 9/11
and I said yes we can trade it happened
to have been in New York at the time and
so part of the magic was that those
three people were the ones that showed
up and also the conversation we had
after of like oh look at this connection
and look at the third piece and I don't
know if that happens and the idea cafe
together tech space but that's part of
the magic it's like oh that resonated
this in me and it brought up this and
like you're one of the other ones in the
world cafe when I don't even remember
someone had like growing up in the
prairies in Canada it was like I'm from
the Prairie something was and her
husband was from the other place the
other third person was from it was it
just like those things happen constantly
and seeing that is part of how humanity
connects and if it's that's a piece of
what the idea Cafe is is connecting
humanity even if we're focusing on
together tech that's that that makes me
think when you talk about connecting
humanity we would want a function that
allows people to communicate afterwards
if we could be randomly putting people
together do we want to have something
like a double opt in trading personal
information yeah I think that's great
yeah I think another option which might
not be big enough for sure is that some
people are gonna want a focused group
that it's the same people they talk with
again and again or let's say if it's
like twenty five people they talk with
way more often so that they feel more
comfortable want to participate but then
there also needs to be a bigger call
verse Asian as long as some people are
transferring I think that's effective
but it's it's about finding what works
for the individual right what's gonna
keep bringing them back to the table
what's gonna be the most beneficial and
I think some people I love random and I
love the group setting I kind of want
both of them and I want you know a small
group of people that we can keep because
then you generate a project and
eventually we have the tools to make a
project and you figure out the people
that you mesh well with and want to
connect with them
there have been game beast conversations
for sure I'm like how do I contact him
or her and then like how and there's no
way to do it besides finding them in the
game be Facebook and then going through
it and I feel like it would be very easy
to create something like that it's just
and I just call attention to earnest who
is saying about that extra time thing
what is it was sorry that he's talking
about the system like chess we have a
fine finite amount of time and then he
talks to the next one he says you can
give extra time at some at a cost that
cost could be the motivational thing I
was talking about for example an idea
someone like Jordan Hall or one of the
Weinsteins is on right and to be like
like maybe we want to hear them talk
more and so we end up getting a time
which wouldn't be the worst they could
do as monopolize half an hour right
which I don't think I need to want to do
it - yeah people can give you extra time
at their own cost ramai on this there we
go
i THS can we call it that because that
seems a little more combative though
that maybe we want to be yeah doesn't
imply a game be space no but but like I
do think back and forth though there
could be an option that brings people
from game into game B that is like idea
chess where people feel like they're
getting at a debate but aren't getting
in a debate it's D UN right yeah thanks
yeah so yeah I'm still kind of stuck on
the harvesting I don't feel that there's
enough stored value I just kind of think
so you know we have you know let's say
we get a billion people involved if I'm
gonna meet with all of them at four at a
time right all right let's say what how
many meetings would I have to have to
meet with someone who has met with you
know to where the communication could
have gone through all the groups Turin
idea has has a good idea that only one
person had could spread to a majority of
the group I'm just trying to think of is
there any other way we want to kind of
harvest I think yes absolutely well
there's a magic idea that someone had in
a group you're like that needs to be up
voted everyone needs to hear that if
there was a way to pull that out and
share it with everyone like if they're
recorded for I don't we can't record in
Zune so that makes it like yeah so why
don't the idea I'm toying with so help
me I'm shaped this if you have any ideas
is that maybe at the end of the
conversation we asked them either as a
group or as individuals you know give us
one or two sentences or ideas that came
out of the group and then that would be
the thing that we feedback or we look
for correlations with other ideas and
then maybe even a different group of
people get together later on or another
that I had was that you have that kind
of time where you have the time where
each person talks and then you have the
time where everyone can talk together
and then maybe at that point there then
we give them like the top five ideas and
then give another period of time for
them to discuss the ideas that have come
from other from you know the complete
history of all the groups before them
interesting another option I had was um
so if we are doing it like a 24 hour
time period or something or whatever
time period it is to be able to say okay
well these people had great like almost
like people audition to be part of the
harvesting team and
so it would be on video like it would be
like hey these people so if you wanted
to watch it that's part of what you
watch then right is people having a
conversation about hey what did I get
out of those conversations is there's
only like four people or maybe there's
multiple conversations going on they're
all recorded and I'll put out there I
don't know how well that works for the
actual harvesting part and the beam so I
have I have an idea they might be in the
beginning would be complicated but they
might be interesting to do it when the
system is already going you can have
some sort of reporter so to speak
someone that's act watching for
highlights of a specific conversation
and then just splits it up into small
snippets so people can review it a
little bit faster and absorb other
conversations it might have missed the
topics that came out of them not you
know because sometimes there's things
that people say that don't connect to
you but will connect someone else
and they might they may not be in
pointed in the in the topics that come
out of each conversation and by having
some sort of snippets of each
conversation that other people can
review we maintain the value of each
conversation for later processing kind
of thing yeah that was one of them last
what it was together tech I don't know
how that would work for that particular
but when it was like more of a how we
create social media for connection but
if you're sharing a story and you're
just essentially that's broken this is
part of why it was broken up into five
minutes without the discussion is if I'm
sharing my story of how I met the love
of my life how I came across having to
try it whatever it is by addiction story
that I'm telling it a five minute
increment in it for me and it's less of
a higher key and following like on
Twitter and YouTube where you have one
person or the ton of followers it's like
hey I love G story we have a lot in
common so I follow you and you might
follow me and so if I'm
part of the idea a fan you like what I
have to say you people are likely to
watch my five minutes than you would
with someone else and so someone you
know I mean you're also drawn to who
they are in saying I would love to be
more connected with them at a table but
maybe that then focuses us in Tamura
like echo chambers tribes yeah yeah
which might be okay also right if our
echo chamber is hey we really like to
talk about food security and we create a
food system that's secure for everyone
I'm okay with that
like that's out but yeah I think that
can also be served at some point really
a lot of people to choose the questions
absolutely so we should probably start
wrapping this up although I feel like an
hour's not enough times yeah talk about
awesome stuff but so too part of my
jumping on what you just said Bentley
part of my idea was actually you're in a
social environment with your friends
whoever and there's an interesting idea
that pops up you can actually grab that
idea create a topic from that idea and
then you can well vote on it grow on it
invite prominent or experienced people
on the subject to bring more
enlightenment to the subject if needed
and so on so just just more things just
keep popping outside that's part of this
process which is I like I can't stop
everything everything you guys everyone
says just keeps turn it off turn off the
brain so everyone have a moment to
debrief and say what but um for next
week do we want to just have a Google
Doc that we put in for the agenda and we
can add notes and say hey here's what
here's what it is are you gonna join us
next week gee are you wanting to
continue talking together tech grow I'm
fully committed in in
whatever this is the whole thing right
not just not the project we're talking
here but it's part of it so I'm doing my
life because obviously I have to leave I
have to eat and so for that III Drive
uber so my sleep schedules are
completely off strange I can actually
because I've been using over as my main
free well I'm getting paid to survey my
customers feel like we're gonna have to
keep bringing each other back to the
topic back specific Bentley's gonna have
to put her topic conversation always I
will never take it the wrong way because
of my brain yet
[Laughter]
so yeah yeah if we could make a agenda
document for the next meeting in that do
you want to just throw it in that folder
Julie do you know that I can do that and
then I'll share it with with geo Swami
to share with him the brainstorming
documents as well he can see those with
them okay and also when I throw one of
the things for each meeting which isn't
necessarily playable this one is if
we're taking anything on right if I'm
like hey here's what I'm gonna do
between now and then which is that I'm
gonna share with gee the document and
start the agenda document and then we
can just add agenda items to there I
think for next time this was a little
bit weird that like this is the first
time we've met Jie and he's just like on
here with us coordinating and I think it
worked okay I think though for the
future we will not do that we will like
someone has to participate like our
nestos participating in the comments and
be part of that process and maybe we can
have conversations with them on like not
at 11:00 a.m. on Friday like another
time period or something and see see if
they resonate with together tech if they
want to help move to like the idea cafe
and the project forward and be updated
updated on it and as we get we can him
twelve people on camera stream you
stops at 6:00 and honestly there's only
so many people we know we can we can
yeah do it with but does that sounds
alright for anyone or anyone want to add
just like keep adding random people I
was doing meeting resumes when I started
doing this and talking to people every
meeting I did I did a meeting with my
resumes some shorten up the meeting into
different topics that we discussed
topics that weren't wrong that I need to
improve on topics questions that they
asked that I couldn't answer and
decisions that were made for that like
you said between this meeting in the
next meeting okay and my takeaway for
the meeting is how I'll put some agenda
topics on the probably one or two all
right what I'm living my life working
with but like I said I'm having this
conversation with my brother tomorrow if
you also know we're dad we talked about
I'm talking about ITA Cafe de YouTube
channel like how to have conversations
on the YouTube channel this is slightly
different which was also part of the
issue of in happiness like how do I own
something without owning it like how do
I work with other people and also move
it forward in my own way and that's part
of game B being social is doing what you
enjoy moving it forward and also be no
nerd but like but I don't want to take
it oh you know like I want it to be ours
and so it's a challenge and I'm also
gonna be looking for a kind of
mastermind group which sounds like what
you and your brother are doing I focus
for that would be my reason score
project but I don't know if you and I
get tired of each other doing that much
together so I thought no no that's
totally fine I'm my brother an hour just
meeting smart it kind of set up like we
did today set up what are these gonna
look like and then put it out for
whoever else wants to come it's gonna be
literally how's your project going what
are you taking on did you do it do you
need help from the crowd to mean help
from each other hands moving moving them
forward I mean one of the projects would
be great to be able to help people build
mastermind groups right around your
goals
that it would be a great first project
but we already picked one you said what
before it until we come to a stopping
point and then yeah good a stopping
point be like we need technology to find
mastermind groups all right yeah thank
you for joining sorry I'm not very good
at I'm glad you guys can read it I
forgot that I'd put that setting on with
idea cafe I don't have it so that people
can or you on at YouTube gee you could
Reaper Nestor the same this particular
video should be alright I don't think we
touched on anything that's that critical
that we need to keep because anything
that's critical like anyone can watch
because he had to get his there were
different dozen report sorry it doesn't
keep like YouTube this is YouTube you're
on YouTube yeah my yeah but that's part
of like having a live you know that that
is very important people to know though
right if I'm sorry if I didn't
communicate that to you well but this is
yes whether it's public live on YouTube
so anyone but dissipate and possibly say
hey I can take that on and do and join
in and you know
fine fine all the ways do that so for
participating so I wasn't able to
participate more with the comment
section and thank you Bentley Angie for
joining I will see you next week and we
also might say goodbye to that the
viewer viewer people bye everybody bye
people and then it was